# **Dinesh Ladi**

Bangalore, India +91 773 898 1316 ladidinesh@gmail.com

Data Scientist with 5.5 years experience in data analyses, machine learning, building data pipelines and deploying models as a service. Spoke at DataBricks and Seoul AI Summits. Currently looking for a data science role where I can help companies/people leverage data to make better decisions using data analyses and machine learning.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Walmart Global Tech

Data Scientist, ML Engineer

Project: Curation of associate ideas using NLP

- Built a system to filter and group high quality ideas using topic modeling, semantic similarity and classification models on s-bert embeddings of user ideas
- Deployed classification model as a REST API using FastAPI, Docker and managed Kubernetes
- Built REST API service monitoring system using Prometheus and Grafana. Deployed alerts to track the health of the service using a managed metrics service

# **Project: Continuous Model Monitoring Framework**

- Wrote frameworks to generate model diagnostics reports and dashboards to identify anomalous/unexpected performance of models for a time series forecasting framework
- Designed triggers to create a JIRA ticket whenever the performance of a model is subpar and not as expected

#### Project: Improvement of Intent Classification Algorithms for a Chatbot

- Built classifiers by fine tuning DistilBERT embeddings for identifying intents in chatbot workflows which in turn improving associate experiences while using chatbot
- Improved latency/memory footprint of the model by quantisation and model pruning techniques

# Project: Optimisation of bags usage at Walmart stores

- Used bin packing algorithms to estimate optimal amount of bags to be used at Walmart store checkout counters
- The solution helped in identifying the stores with high over-usage of bags and keep on check on the

#### **Actify Data Labs**

Bangalore, India

Bangalore, India May 2020–Present

Data Scientist

Aug 2018-May 2020

# **Project: Crop Classification using Satellite Imagery**

- Built a data pipeline to generate spectral indices, create features, train models and score on unseen satellite images
- Used custom metrics (combination of precision and recall) to estimate optimal threshold
- Reduced the huge number of man-hours taken to identify and geospatial labeling of crops across various regions in the country. Manual geo labelling of crops for each district takes around 4-5 man hours. Reduced it down to less than 1 hour without compromising precision and recall.

#### **Project: Interactive Decision Tree**

- Developed an interactive drag and drop decision tree tool for segmentation of data for business users The features include delete, add, cut and copy a subtree from the tree and export the rules to segment the data
- Conceptualized, designed and developed the complete product module including algorithm design, UI
  design and scalability for larger data
- The product is sold to one of the cab sharing unicorn in the country

Opera Solutions Noida, India

Analytics Specialist

Jan 2018-August 2018

# Project: Revenue management of health care providers

- Developed an ensemble of Random Forest and Logistic Regression to identify potential revenue items that are missing from a given bill and provide recommendations to the front line accounts
- More than 85 % of the recommendations were correct in identifying missed bill items. This led to significant revenue enhancement for the health care providers

# **Cognizant Technology Solutions**

Chennai, India

Analyst

July 2016–Jan 2018

# **Project: Ad-Viewership Analytics**

- Built data pipelines to curate, consolidate and process ad-viewership data across multiple viewing channels
- Tools used: Hive SQL, Hadoop, Unix Scripting

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS/COURSES**

- Languages: python, R, pyspark, SQL, unix
- **Tools**: Docker, Prometheus, Grafana, R-Shiny
- **Libraries**: pandas, scikit-learn, fastapi, streamlit
- **Courses**: Statistical Learning (Stanford), Deep Learning Specialization (Coursera)

#### **EDUCATION**

IIT Bombay Mumbai, India

Bachelors of Technology & Masters of Technology in Energy Science and Engineering (GPA: 8/10)

2011-2016

#### **CONFERENCES**

- Conversational AI using transformer models Seoul AI Summit 2020
- Conversational AI with transformer models DataBricks Data + AI Summit North America Chapter 2021